tec-it.com 2019-06-10

# Terms of Use and Privacy Policy for TEC-IT Websites

##  Privacy Policy 

The protection of your personal data is of special concern to us, therefore we process your data exclusively based on the legal regulations. In this privacy statement we inform you about the most important aspects of data processing within the framework of our website, apps, add-ins, "Software as a Service" applications (in short SaaS) and our webshop. 

### Purpose and Legal Basis

Data processing is based on the statutory provisions of § 96 (3) TKG and Art. 6 para. 1 lit a (consent) and / or lit b (necessary for fulfillment of the contract) of the GDPR. 

The data provided by you is required to fulfill the contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures (such as the download of demo versions of our software). Without this data, we cannot conclude a contract with you. 

###  Your Rights 

You are entitled to information, correction, deletion, restriction, data portability, revocation and opposition. If you believe that the processing of your data violates data protection law or your privacy claims have otherwise been violated in any way, you can contact the relevant supervisory authority (Data Protection Authority [ https://www.dsb.gv.at ](https://www.dsb.gv.at/ "https://www.dsb.gv.at")) for a complaint. 

### Contact

Your contact person regarding this Privacy Policy is 

Mr Guenter Kriegl  
TEC-IT Datenverarbeitung GmbH,  
Hans-Wagner-Strasse 6, A-4400 Steyr  
t: +43-7252-72720, e: [office@tec-it.com](mailto:office@tec-it.com "Office@tec-it.com")

You may exercise all rights by e-mail, personal contact, by postal mail or via the contact form. In order to ensure that we only respond to legitimate affected persons, we reserve the right to verify your identity.

### Data Storage 

Personal information we collect may include: 

  * Personal or business contact information (such as name, company name, physical address, email address, instant messenger and social media handles, telephone or fax numbers) 
  * Personal or business contact information of others to whom we are asked to send information 
  * Username and credentials for accessing our website and SaaS applications and services 
  * Social media content and other data posted on our official social media sites or otherwise on the internet, and data (such as email address and other information you allow to be shared) that we receive through social media apps, tools, widgets and plug-ins (including third-party login services such as "Login via Facebook"). 
  * Payment information (including payment card details or number and invoicing address when using online payment service providers) as well as financial information (such as bank account numbers)
  * Tax identification number 
  * Other personal information provided to us in connection with the purchase of a product or service on a voluntary basis
  * IP address when accessing our online sites and add-ins

### Data Transmission 

Personal data will not be transmitted to third parties, with the exception of the transmission

  * of the account and payment card data to the banking / payment service providers for the settlement of payments and the collection, 
  * to the transport companies / shipping companies we use to deliver goods or data carriers, 
  * to our tax advisor to fulfill our tax obligations,
  * to our legal advisor for clarification of legal issues,
  * for sending newsletters (see below),
  * for the analysis of the website (see below),
  * to the document shredder commissioned by us.

### Storage Duration 

We store the collected data for different lengths of time according to need and application. In general, all data from contractual relationships are kept until expiry of the retention period relating to commercial or tax law (7 years). In addition, it applies that 

  * In any case, payment card / credit card numbers are only to be stored for the duration of the processing, for a maximum of 2 weeks 
  * all data from contracts for software licenses with unlimited validity (lifetime licenses) can be stored permanently 
  * all data published on social media channels and / or on our web site can be stored permanently 
  * all contract data for SaaS applications may be stored for the duration of the contract or, if technically supported, until the data is deleted by the contractor itself 
  * Data of persons with whom there is no contractual relationship can be stored for three years to process the request and in case of follow-up and liability issues 

### Newsletter 

You can subscribe to our newsletter via our website. For this, we need your e-mail address and your declaration that you agree with the subscription to the newsletter. In order to provide you with targeted information, we also collect and process voluntary information about your interests. 

The following information is intended to inform you about the registration, shipping and evaluation procedures as well as your right of objection. By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described. 

The newsletter is distributed via MailChimp, a newsletter shipping platform of The Rocket Science Group, LLC, 675 Ponce de Leon Ave NE, Suite 5000, Atlanta, GA 30308 USA. The e-mail addresses of our Newsletter recipients, as well as their other information described herein, are stored on the servers of MailChimp in the USA. MailChimp uses this information to send and evaluate the newsletters on our behalf.

We have concluded a data processing agreement with MailChimp under which MailChimp pledges to protect the data of our users, to process it in accordance with its privacy policy on our behalf and, in particular, not to disclose it to third parties. The MailChimp privacy policy apply as well as the MailChimp PRIVACY SHIELD (EU-US data protection agreement).

The duration of data storage is until canceled. 

You can terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time i.e. revoke your consent. At the same time, your consent to sending it via MailChimp and the statistical analyses will lapse. Use the cancelation link at the end of each newsletter or contact us. 

### Cookies 

TEC-IT Websites are using cookies. A cookie is a small file, which is stored by the web-server on your computer/hard drive. Cookies cannot be used to execute programs or to spread viruses. Cookies are assigned to a specific user of a TEC-IT Website. One of the major reasons for using cookies is to improve the usability of Websites and to save time. The user of TEC-IT web pages has the option to accept or reject cookies. Most web browsers accept cookies automatically. However, browsers can be set by the user to only allow cookies from certain web pages. If the user decides to reject cookies from TEC-IT web pages, it may happen that the use of TEC-IT web pages is not or only partially possible. Certain cookies are used to identify a browser session (session cookies) and are deleted from your hard disk after the browser has been closed. 

### Log files

Every time you access our website, usage data is transmitted by the browser and stored in so-called server log files. The data sets that are stored contain the following data: date and time of retrieval, name of page accessed, IP address, referrer URL (origin URL from which you were redirected to our website), the amount of data transferred, product and version information of the used browser. 

Subject to any legal retention requirements, users' IP addresses will be deleted after the end of use, at the latest after 30 days. 

We occasionally evaluate these log file records anonymously in order to improve our web presence or to find and correct errors. In addition, we can also detect and fix any errors in our web services faster by analyzing the log files. 

## Google Analytics

#### Web Analytics Service 

This website uses the "Google Analytics" service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) to analyze users' website usage. The relationship with the web analytics service provider is based on the adequacy decision of the European Commission (in the case of the USA: "Privacy Shield"). 

#### IP Anonymization 

This site uses IP anonymization. Your IP address will therefore be shortened by Google before further use within member states of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area and thus used only anonymously. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there. 

On our behalf, Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide us with other services related to website activity and internet usage. 

The (shortened) IP address provided by your browser as part of Google Analytics will not be merged with other data provided by Google. 

#### Cookies 

Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files stored on your computer that allow us to analyze the use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is usually sent to a server from Google in the US and stored there. 

For more information on how to handle user data on Google Analytics, please refer to the Google Privacy Policy: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

####  Browser Plugin 

You can prevent the storage of cookies by a corresponding setting of your browser software; however, please note that if you do this, you may not be able to use all the features of this website to the fullest extent possible. You may also prevent the collection of the cookie-generated and website-related information (including your IP address) to Google and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser add-on from the following link: [ http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en ](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en "Google Browser Plugin")

####  Opt Out 

As an alternative to the browser plug-in or within browsers on mobile devices, please click this link to prevent future collection of your data by Google Analytics (the opt-out only works in the browser and only for this domain). Therefor an opt-out cookie is stored on your device. If you delete your cookies in this browser, you must click this link again. 

##  Google AdWords 

We use Google AdWords, an online advertising program from Google. Google AdWords uses cookies to analyze the use of the website. A cookie is set when you visit our website through a Google ad. Cookies of this type lose their validity after 30 days and are not used for personal identification. If you visit certain webpages of our website and the cookie has not expired yet, Google and we may recognize that you clicked on the ad and were redirected to this page. You can prevent the storage of cookies by setting your browser software accordingly (see Web Analysis). 

Each Google AdWords customer receives a different cookie. Cookies can not be tracked through AdWords advertisers' websites. The information gathered using the conversion cookie is used to generate conversion statistics for AdWords advertisers who have opted for conversion tracking. Advertisers will see the total number of users who clicked on their ad and were redirected to a conversion tracking tag page. However, they do not receive any information that personally identifies Internet users. Internet users who do not want to participate in tracking can deactivate the Google Conversion Tracking cookie through the settings of the Internet browser used. These internet users will not be included in the conversion tracking statistics. 

## Google reCAPTCHA

To prevent spam and abuse, we use the service "Google reCAPTCHA" (Version 3) of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google") on our websites. This function is primarily used to distinguish whether an entry (e.g. in a contact form) is made by a natural person or is abused by automated processing. For this reCAPTCHA analyzes the behavior of the website visitor on the basis of different characteristics (duration of stay, mouse movements...). The service includes the transmission of the IP address and possibly further data required by Google for the reCAPTCHA service to Google.

The reCAPTCHA analyses start with entering the website and run completely in the background, website visitors are not informed separately. Data processing is based on Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The website operator has a legitimate interest in protecting his web offers from abusive automated spying and from SPAM.

Additional information about Google reCAPTCHA and Google's privacy policy can be found at [https://www.google.com/recaptcha](https://www.google.com/recaptcha/ "Https://www.google.com/recaptcha") and <https://policies.google.com/privacy>.

## Bing Ads

This website uses the Conversion-Tracking Technology “Bing Ads” of Microsoft Corporation. For this purpose, a cookie is placed on your computer if you visited our website via Bing or Yahoo. By means of this small text file, information about the use of our website (i.e. the pages you visit) is stored by Bing Ads for 180 days and then deleted. This information includes, but is not limited to, the URL of the page visited, the URL of the referrer page, and your IP address. However, we do not obtain any information by which users can be identified personally.

If you do not wish to participate in the tracking, you may object to this usage by easily deactivating the Bing Ads conversion tracking cookie via your internet browser and your user settings. Using the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) opt-out page [http://www. networkadvertising.org/choices/](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ "Network Advertising Initiative") you can check which of the participating pages set cookies in your browser and disable them. You can access Microsoft's privacy policy for the data collected by following this link: [https://privacy.microsoft.com/de-de/privacystatement/](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-us/privacystatement/ "Microsoft Privacy Policy"). 

## Use of Social Media Plugins

We use a video viewing plugin operated by YouTube (LLC, 901 Cherry Ave., San Bruno, CA 94066, USA, www.youtube.com). By clicking on `Accept` in the cookie banner of our websites (or in the video), you consent to the processing of data by the social network operator (YouTube). Only _after consenting_ a connection is established from your browser to YouTube and data transferred to the operator of the social network. The consent remains stored in your browser via cookies.

The social network receives information about your visit to our websites via the plugin. If you are logged in to YouTube, your visit can be assigned to your social network account. Any interactions with the plugin can be saved by the network operator. Information about the use of the data collected by the social network can be found on the company's website (YouTube.com) in the "Privacy Policy" section: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.
